Stephen Thompson

Location: Chicago, IL 60647

Portfolio: https://sgthompson.herokuapp.com

Phone: (410) 688-1617 | Email: drsgthompson@gmail.com

GitHub: http://github.com/SThompsonChicago | LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/drsgthompson

Summary

Full-stack web developer living in Chicago. PhD in applied mathematics. Over five years of experience teaching mathematics and statistics, and three years writing code. Published research in peer-reviewed journals on fixed-point theory, mathematical epidemiology, differential equations and economics. Recently finished the full stack boot camp at Northwestern University.

Technical Skills

JavaScript, Node, Python, React, MERN stack, SQL, Git, HTML, CSS, jQuery, MongoDB, NoSQL, Visual Studio and GraphQL.

Soft Skills

Patient, innovative, and able to see the big picture.

Projects

React.js Macroeconomic Forecaster: React.js application that allows user to choose parameters for a macroeconomic model, run simulations, and view the results as an animation as the model is being solved (uses Runge-Kutta method).

Deployed app: https://sthompsonchicago.github.io/macro-disequilibrium/ GitHub repo: https://github.com/SThompsonChicago/macro-disequilibrium/

MERN Blog: Full-stack application that allows a user to create an account, write blog posts and view posts by others. Created using the MERN stack and a MongoDB database.

Deployed app: https://vast-mountain-43651.herokuapp.com/ GitHub repo: https://github.com/SThompsonChicago/mern-blog

Python Simulation Space: Full-stack app created with Python/Django. Allows user to choose simulation models from a database, and then run them within the web browser.

Deployed app: https://singwithsims.herokuapp.com/

GitHub repo: https://github.com/SThompsonChicago/python-simulation-space

Education

Certificate, Full-Stack Web Development Northwestern University, 2021

Doctor of Philosophy, Applied Mathematics University of Maryland, Baltimore County (UMBC), 2013

Professional Experience

Mathematics Instructor, 2015-2021

University of Maryland, Baltimore County (Baltimore, Maryland)

Developed student mastery of advance math (including ordinary and partial differential equations, linear algebra and more). Instructed classes with up to 120 students. Oversaw two teaching assistants per semester, as well as one or more graders at a time.

High School Teacher, 2019-2020
Baltimore City Public Schools (Baltimore, Maryland)
Motivated over 60 students to understand algebra and meet graduation requirements.

Affiliate Faculty, 2017-2019 Loyola University, Maryland (Baltimore, Maryland) Taught a variety of undergraduate calculus courses.